翻译：小布拿拿      Tiogy      红豆包      斯人
翻译&校对&总监：Iz
后期：斯人     时间轴：深夏桃子
《开心汉堡店》第五季第七集
这只老耗子
除虫害公司
-55  -明显的白
-55... - Distinguished gray.
-56  -不明显的白
- 56... - Undistinguished gray.
别数我的白头发了
Hey! Stop counting my gray hairs.
我们倒想数老爸的  但他的太容易掉了
We would count Dad's, but his hair is so fragile.
没有啊  天哪  掉了一丛
No, it's not. Oh, my God, a clump.
老妈  我能用这袋子套我的雷娘军制服吗
Mom, can I use this bag to store my Thundergirls uniform?
我还是不敢相信你退出了雷娘军
I still can't believe you quit the Thundergirls.
你要把你的雷娘装收起来了吗
Are you gonna put away your thunder-wear?
恭喜你离开了那个异教团  蒂娜
Congratulations on getting out of that cult, Tina.
我想我是年龄大了  不适合参加了
I was just getting too old for it, I guess.
你年龄大了是什么意思
What do you mean "Too old"?
老爸  蒂娜都13岁了
Dad, Tina's 13.
在雷娘军里  那就等于40岁了
In Thundergirl years, that's, like, 40.
现在的40岁和38岁一样吃香好吗
Hey. 40 is the new 38.
是啊  现在38岁才是春天呢
Yeah, and 38 is the new...
-没错  -蒂娜  发生了什么事
- Yeah. - Tina, what happened?
我和年轻的女孩间
There may have been a culture clash
可能有些文化冲突
between me and the younger girls.
我不觉得自己是根插在泥潭里的棍子
I mean, I wouldn't say I was a stick in the mud...
也指古板无趣的人
看哪  泥潭里有根棍子  在过去
Look, a stick in the mud! In the old days,
雷娘军就是用这个做日晷的
that's how a Thundergirl made a sun dial.
真不错  蒂娜
Oh, that's nice, Tina.
大家看到蒂娜的棍子了吗
Did everyone see Tina's stick?
看到了
Yes...
不管怎样  现在我的日程表有空闲了
Anyway, now that I have an opening in my schedule,
就有更多的时间来陪你们了
I can spend more time with you guys.
好吧  很好  吉恩
Okay, great. Gene,
我们这周什么安排
what do we got going on this week?
你的洗澡夜我可以帮你换到别的时间
You've got a bath night I can move around,
但这周你已经推迟两次了
but you've already moved it twice.
直接取消吧  蒂娜  欢迎加入
Let's cancel it. Tina, you're in.
-好吧  -我知道我要做什么了
- Okay. - Well, I know what I'm doing.
我要给理发店的格雷琴打电话
I'm calling Gretchen at the salon.
和白发说拜拜吧  孩子们
Say good-bye to the gray, kids.
好吧  但我要留着这根
Fine. But I'm keeping this one.
哎哟  是根黑发
Oops, it's a black one.
我把它放回去
I'll put it back.
发桶理发店
格雷琴  真高兴你帮我处理掉了那些白发
Gretchen, I'm so glad you got rid of those old-lady grays.
-再也不想看到白发了  -准备好了吗
- No more salt with this pepper. - You ready?
准备好了
Ready!
我的老天爷啊
Oh! Oh, my God!
这是什么啊
Yeah, uh-oh!
出了点问题
L-Little mistake.
把我弄得像只斑马一样
You made me look like a zebra!
-快重弄  -别慌  别慌
- Fix it! - Don't panic. Don't panic.
-求你了 重弄吧  -别慌  琳
- Please, fix it.  - Don't panic, Lin.
-重弄  -我知道  我知道怎么办了
- Fix it! - I know... I know what I can do.
-染回来  -不
- Dye it back! - No.
-染成金色的  -什么
- Dye it blonde. - What?
相信我  变金发后整个世界都会不一样
Trust me. Everything is better as a blonde.
看什么都觉得好
Everything looks better.
-吃什么也都觉得香  -比如说呢
- Everything tastes better. - Like what?
-番茄酱包  止咳药  -番茄酱
- Ketchup packets, cough drops... - Ketchups?
来吧  染吧  染吧
Come on. Do it, do it, do it,
染吧  染吧  染吧  染吧
do it, do it, do it, do it, do it,
-染吧  染吧  -好吧  好吧
- do it, do it, do it. - Yeah! Yeah!
-耶  耶  -管它呢
- Yeah! Yeah! - What the hell?
能给我看看菜单吗
Can I get a menu, please?
天哪
Oh, my God.
是中年芭比老妈
It's middle-aged Mom Barbie!
我喜欢你的新发型
I like your hair.
很配你的牙
It matches your teeth.
多谢  蒂娜
Thank you, Tina.
你不觉得
Sort of an extreme reaction
你对几根白发的反应太极端了吗
to a few gray hairs, don't you think?
-不觉得  -目前为止还未体会到乐趣
- No. - I’m not having more fun yet.
-等下  有了  -看吧
- Wait! Yes, I am! - You see?
吉恩懂欣赏了  鲍鲍  你也试试
Gene gets it. Bobby, you try.
不  我看不用了
No, I don't think so.
试试嘛  蒂娜呢
come on! Tina?
我能等药水味儿散掉后再试吗
Can I do it later after the chemical smell wears off?
露易丝
Louise?
谁在说话  老妈在哪
Who said that? Where's Mom?
-蒂娜  -垃圾在说话
- Tina? - Trash?
不  我是吉妮  雷娘军成员
No, it's Ginny. From Thundergirls.
吉妮  你在我家后院
Ginny? What are you doing in our alley pretending
扮垃圾做什么
to be the trash?
我不能冒险让人看到我
I couldn't risk anyone seeing me.
我来这里是因为
I'm here because
119团有内鬼[痣]
Troop 119 has... a... mole.
我还以为凯蒂那长的是雀斑呢
I thought Katie just had a beauty mark.
不  我是说内鬼
No, a mole-mole.
我觉得我们团里有人一直在暗中监视我们
I think someone in our troop has been spying on us.
为我们的劲敌  257团  提供情报
For our archrivals, Troop 257.
257团  他们是镇上最厉害的团
Troop 257? They're the toughest troop in town.
我听说他们在大火中
I heard they hold hot dogs in the fire
赤手举着热狗
with their bare hands.
是的  我在商场碰到过他们的成员
Yeah. I saw one of them at the mall,
我躲在了衣架中间
and I hid in the middle of a rack of clothes.
但是119团里怎么会有内鬼呢
But how could there be a mole in Troop 119?
我们拉小指承诺过永远是朋友的啊
We pinky-swore we'd be friends forever.
除了那个没有小指
Except that one girl
后来搬走的女生
who didn't have a pinky and moved away.
她真是命运多舛
She had a lot going on.
蒂娜  我知道这样说听起来很疯狂
Tina, I know it sounds crazy,
但这是唯一的解释
but it's the only explanation.
你知道我们每年的饼干销售额有多差劲吗
You know how every year our cookie sales are pathetic?
知道  我们一直那样
Yeah, that's our thing.
都是因为有内鬼
It's because of the mole.
她把我们的饼干销售点泄露给了257团
She's been giving away our cookie leads to Troop 257.
上周以前我都还不能百分之分肯定
I wasn't 100% certain until last week...
我刚换新工作  那儿有很多饼干爱好者
I was at my new job. Lot of cookie lovers there.
我闻得出来
I could smell it.
于是我安排了119团
I arranged for Troop 119 to come
来我办公室卖饼干
to my office and sell cookies.
这可是笔大买卖
It was gonna be a huge score.
但当我们出现时
But when we showed up,
猜猜谁抢先了我们一步
guess who beat us to the punch.
-257团  -是的
- Troop 257? - Yes.
这下我在自己的休息室里
I had to eat Troop 257's cookies
都只能吃257团的饼干了
from my own break room.
你也可以不吃
Well, you didn't have to. You...
-我必须吃  蒂娜  -对不起
- I had to, Tina. I had to! -  I’m so sorry.
我和团里所有的女生都聊过了
I've talked to all the girls in the troop,
但我不能排除她们中任何一人
and I can't rule out any of them.
谁都有可能是内鬼
The mole could be anybody.
除了你  蒂娜
Except you, Tina.
-那真好  -你不可能是内鬼  因为
- Oh, good. - It can't be you because you left the troop
你在那丢人的办公室事件发生前就离开了
before the humiliating office incident.
所以我需要你回来
That's why I need you to rejoin.
和她们谈谈  找到内鬼
Talk to the girls. Find the mole.
我吗  回去  可我的伤口还没愈合呢
Me? Rejoin? But my wounds are still fresh.
我的意思是  我不是真的受了伤
I mean, I don't actually have wounds.
即使我有  我也会做急救处理
And if I did, I would do first aid on them
因为我有创可贴
because I have that patch.
蒂娜  每年开饼干大会
Tina, every year at the cookie jamboree,
我都得向别人解释
I've had to explain
为啥我们销量最低
why we have the lowest sales of anyone.
我再也不要了  不要
I'm not doing it anymore. I'm not!
如果找不到内鬼
Now, if I don't find the mole,
我就
I'm just... I'm gonna...
我就解散我们的团
I'm gonna dissolve the troop!
解散119团
Dissolve Troop 119?
-不可以  -我偏要
- No, you can't! - Well, I'm gonna do it!
好吧  我帮你找内鬼
Fine, I'll help you find your mole.
太好了  谢谢你
Great. Okay. Thank you.
记着  这事儿不能告诉任何人
And remember, don't tell anyone anything about this.
明白  你知  我知  日记知
Got it. This is between you, me, and my journal.
-不行  日记也不行  -我说秘密日记
- No. No journal. - I meant my secret journal.
你都不知道的
The one you don't know about.
你刚告诉我了
You just told me about it.
好吧  那我就写在信里
Okay. I'll just write it in a letter
然后寄给我自己  不打开
and mail it to myself and not open it.
不行  写哪里都不行
No. Don't write it anywhere.
好  好  好
Okay. Cool, cool, cool, cool. Cool.
初版《雷娘军指南》  我们重出江湖啦
We're back in, original copy of the Thundergirls handbook
大家都认为你又老又过气  像我一样
that the other girls think is old and outdated, like me.
-击掌  -蒂娜
- High five. - Hey, Tina.
我们打算去捡贝壳  给我做件贝壳比基尼
We're gonna go find shells and make me a shell bikini.
要一起来吗
Want to come?
咋又穿上雷娘军的制服了
What's with the Thundergirls uniform?
我打算重返雷娘军
I decided to rejoin the Thundergirls.
什么  别  蒂娜
What? No, Tina.
你才刚退出啊  怎么又要回去
You just got out. Now you're going back in?
美国橄榄球运动员  多次退役又归队
这不成雷娘军版的法弗了吗
You're like the Brett Favre of Thundergirls.
我没办法袖手旁观
I couldn't stay away.
虽然不是因为什么奇怪的理由
I mean, it's not for any weird reason.
并不是因为有内鬼什么的
It's not like there's a mole in our troop
得我暗中回去抓住她什么的
and I'm going undercover to catch her or anything.
等等  你们队里有内鬼  雷娘内鬼
Wait, wait, wait. Your troop has a mole? A thunder-mole?
你怎么得出这个结论的
What? Where'd you get that idea?
怎么  她泄露你们的饼干销售情报了
Is she giving away your cookie secrets or something?
饼干情报是我的艺名
That's my stage name, Cookie Secrets.
被你说中了  泄露给了257团
Actually, yes. To Troop 257.
别说是我说的
But you didn't hear it from me.
蒂娜  你真是最不合适
Tina, you're the worst person
去潜伏抓内鬼的人了
to go undercover to catch a mole.
你刚把整件事都告诉我们了
You just spilled your whole story to us.
给你们套出来的
You guys were all over me about it!
听我说
All right, here's what you got to do.
你得拿出你狂暴的那一面
You got to go in there and rattle some cages.
抓住那些雷娘军一顿狂摇
Grab those Thundergirls and shake 'em
直到有人认罪
till you shake out a confession!
是我  我就是内鬼
It's me! It's me! I'm the mole!
不  露易丝  我得悄无声息地进行
No, Louise. I have to go about this delicately.
让她以为自己很安全  然后自投罗网
I have to make the mole feel safe so she comes to me.
蒂娜  你真的需要我助你一臂之力
Tina, you so need me on this.
一切听我的指令行事
Do what I say and say what I say,
晚饭前就能结案
and we'll have this case cracked by dinnertime.
露易丝  这是雷娘军的内务
Louise, it's Thundergirls stuff.
你不会明白的
You wouldn't understand.
我自己能搞定
I can handle this on my own.
你不用插手
You don't need to get involved.
得了  蒂娜  我才不会插手
Tina, please. I'm not gonna get involved.
我又不会马上出门
It's not like I'm gonna go out right now
去买一套雷娘军制服
and buy a Thundergirls uniform
然后出现在你们的会议上
and then show up at your meeting later.
-得了吧  -那就好
- I mean, come on. - Okay, good.
孩子们  我觉得你们以后可以叫我金妈
Hey! I was thinking you guys could start calling me Blom.
因为我是金发  又是你们妈  明白吗
Because I'm blonde and I'm your mom. Get it?
妈  我们正忙着呢
Mom, we're busy in here.
别跟这么跟金妈讲话
Hey, don't talk to Blom like that.
谢谢你  吉恩
Thank you, Gene.
好了  蒂娜  你归队了
Okay, Tina. You're back.
额  不是真的归队  只是找内鬼
I mean, you're not back. You're here to find the mole.
但也可以唱唱歌  做些点心
I mean, maybe sing some songs and make some s'mores.
不过主要任务是找内鬼
But mostly to find the mole.
真好  接力编辫子还在继续呢
Hey, good to see the braid trains are still running.
蒂娜  快进来  大伙快看谁回来了
Tina, come on in. Look who's back, everyone.
大家好  你们酷炫的小伙伴蒂娜回来了
Hey, guys. It's your cool, young, hip friend Tina.
能听懂么
Can you dig it?
你接替我的位子继续编吧
You can take my place on the braid train.
我得去做点心了
I have to get snack ready.
希望你们喜欢鳄梨酱[内鬼]薯片
I hope you all like chips with guaca-mole.
吉妮  你知道吗  每次碗里最后
Ginny, did you know that the last chip
一块薯片  93%的成分都是皮肤细胞
in the bowl is 93% skin cells?
乔迪  我知道
Yes, Jodi.
真好  我们玩个游戏吧
This is nice. Oh, hey, should we play a game
说一说彼此内心深处最黑暗的秘密
where we tell each other our deepest, darkest secrets?
开玩笑啦  除非你们愿意
Just kidding. I mean, unless you want to.
这里还有多余的空位吗
Room for one more on that Thundertrain?
你好
Oh. Hi.
你是
Are you...
没人跟我说
Nobody told me...
我没有
I-I don't have any...
文件吗  不要紧亲爱的
Paperwork? Don't worry about it, honey.
我的律师马上送过来
My lawyer's sending it over.
来见见你们最新最嫩的雷娘成员  我
Meet your newest, greenest, preteenest Thundergirl, me.
不  我是说  欢迎
No! I mean, welcome.
谢谢
Thank you.
露易丝  真不敢相信你也来了
Louise, I can't believe you joined my Thundergirls troop.
我不是说我自己能搞定干吗
I told you I had everything under control.
还有  你绶带戴得一塌糊涂
Also, your sash is a disaster.
快把我逼疯了
That was driving me crazy.
别管这破绶带了  蒂娜
Tina, forget about the stupid sash.
抓内鬼才最重要
We've got a mole to catch, girl!
我们是内鬼监察队
You and I are the mole patrol.
来吧  一起来
Come on! Do it!
-哔  -不对  看我的口型
- Beep, beep. - No, l... Look at my mouth.
我们还是做正事吧
Let's just get down to business.
现在我们所掌握的情况是
All right, here's what we know:
119团有个内奸
Troop 119 has a mole
把情报泄露给了257团
who is giving away secrets to Troop 257.
到底是谁在从中作梗
So, which one of you is sabotaging our cookie sales?
凯蒂  她是数学火箭班的
Katie. She's in honors math.
也可以说  她是个邪恶的精灵鬼
Or...she's an evil genius.
朱莉  她是个话唠
Julie. She's kind of a motor mouth.
是她大嘴巴泄露了情报吗
Is she yapping about troop secrets?
丽娜  她个子很小
Rena. She's a little on the short side.
但也许她在说大话
But maybe she's telling tall tales.
乔迪  总戴着一副橡胶手套
Jodi. She wears rubber gloves
因为她有严重洁癖
because she's a major germophobe.
也可能是为了不留下指纹
Or so she won't leave any fingerprints behind.
最后是莫莉
And finally there's Molly.
她是双重关节[关节非常灵活]
She's double-jointed.
也许是两面派
Or a double-crosser.
她们中任何一个都可能是内奸
Any one of them could be the mole.
-但是谁呢  -看看这位嫌疑人
- But who? - Look at this suspicious character.
-吉恩  -就带我一个不行嘛
- Gene... - Just let me into your world!
好吧  你去检查她们的垃圾
Fine. You... go through everyone's trash, okay?
-找找有没有...  -吃剩的三明治吗
- Dig around. Look for... - Half-eaten sandwiches?
-不  找线索  -两者可以同时进行嘛
- No, clues! They're not mutually exclusive!
这么说  大家都同意只抓内奸
So we all agree, a surgical mole removal
不伤及无辜  对吧露易丝
and no one gets hurt. Right, Louise?
我们都同意
Yeah, we all agree.
但要是我这么做了呢
But what if I just did this?
再各个击破
And now we shoot them.
开个玩笑  只是感觉那样还蛮好玩的
Just kidding. I kind of thought that'd be more fun.
我们还是去绊老爸吧
Let's go trip Dad.
*金发飘飘  优雅妖娆*
*So blonde, so delicate and blonde.*
面包在这  贝尔彻先生
Here are your buns, Mr. Belcher.
你为什么喊我贝尔彻先生
Why are you calling me Mr. Belcher?
-别说我是你老板  -你是我老板
- Don't say 'cause I'm your boss... - 'Cause you're my boss...
-你是我的性感助手 -我是你的性感助手
- And you're my sexy assistant. - And I'm your sexy assistant.
对  我会扒光衣服
Yes. I'm gonna take off all my clothes
在冷库那等你
and wait for you in the walk-in.
我觉得这不是个好主意
I don't think that's a good idea to...
打到我眼睛了
That hit my eye.
-是的  必须的  -真的很疼
- Yes, it did. - It really hurts.
我看看  大男孩
Let me look at it, you big baby.
-我现在是金发护士  -不
- I'm the blonde nurse! - No.
现在是第二次世界大战
It's World War II.
-你眼睛中枪  -不不不
- You got shot in the eye. - No, no.No.
我俩激情四射
The chemistry between us is smoldering.
我的天
Oh, my God.
让我看看
Let me see it.
这种角色扮演对我没用
This... The fantasy doesn't work.
-为什么  -要是我眼睛中弹了
- Why? - I-I feel like if I got shot in the eye,
我就只想让你治治我的眼睛  和脑子
I would want you to help my eye. And my brain.
我又不懂  我又不是医生
Well, I don't know. I'm not a freaking doctor.
我是护士  鲍勃
I'm a nurse, Bob.
那你能请个医生来吗
Well, can you get a doctor?
-因为我需要医生  -等等
- 'Cause I need a doctor. - Oh, wait.
-我是医生  -不  别
- I'm a doctor. - No. Not...
-让我来瞧瞧  -天哪
- Let me look at that over here. - Oh, my God.
手链串的怎么样了  姑娘们
How are your bracelets coming along, girls?
-挺好的  -很好  -挺好的
- Fine. - Good. - Fine.
我要把我的手链给我的小妹
I'm giving my bracelet to my new baby sister.
她超萌  但她现在还没什么首饰呢
She's so cute and she has almost no jewelry.
我要把我的给凯蒂
I'm giving mine to Katie.
我要把我的给朱莉
I'm giving mine to Julie.
-真巧  -真巧
- Jinx! - Jinx!
不对
I mean...
是时候开始行动了
Okay, time to put the plan into action.
第一阶段  取得她们的信任
Phase one. Get them to trust me.
-这手链真漂亮  朱莉  -谢谢
- That's a pretty bracelet, Julie. - Thanks!
第一阶段完成
Okay, phase one complete.
第二阶段  让所有人反目成仇
Phase two, turn everyone against each other
-让内奸自动现行  -等等  什么
- until the mole is flushed out. - Wait, what?
凯蒂和我说你的手链很丑
Katie told me she thinks your bracelet's ugly.
-不是吧  -是的
- Oh, no. - Oh, yes.
我发现了超酷的东西
Okay, I found some pretty cool stuff,
还把每个人的垃圾都整理成堆了
and I've organized everyone's trash into piles.
-那是谁的垃圾  -乔迪的
- Whose trash is that? - Jodi's.
-有点意思  -都很有意思
- Interesting. - It's all interesting.
每堆都有各自的故事
Each pile tells a story.
比如  昨晚丽娜吃了炸鸡  就这样
For example, last night, Rena had chicken. The end.
露易丝  119团的成员都反目了
Louise! Everyone in Troop 119 hates each other.
这正是我担心的
This is exactly what I was worried about.
我觉得你想说的是
I believe what you're trying to say is,
"谢谢  露易丝
"Thank you. Thank you, Louise,
谢谢你帮我调查内奸"
for helping me smoke out the mole."
露易丝  你会毁了我们整个团的
Louise, you're going to destroy the troop!
你何必那么在乎那个团呢
Why do you care so much about the troop, anyway?
她们拒绝了你啊  记得不
They rejected you, remember?
119团把我塑造成了现在这个女人
Troop 119 shaped me into the woman I am.
我还以为是你内衣的功劳呢
I thought your underwear did that.
蒂娜  我们试过你的方法了
Tina, we tried things your way.
并没有
No, we didn't.
我脑子里过了一遍  根本没用
I did in my head, and it didn't work.
等找出内奸你就会谢谢我了
You'll thank me later when we remove the mole.
换个话题  跟我说实话
Changing subject. Be honest,
我看起来像杰西卡吗
do I look like a Jessica?
这样真好
This is nice.
等下  露易丝人呢  乔迪人呢
Wait. Where's Louise? And where's Jodi?
凯蒂  你能帮我看下我的带子吗
Katie, will you watch my lanyard?
我去去就回
I'll be right back.
来捣个乱吧
Let's mess with her lanyard.
我知道你有秘密
I know you know something.
快告诉我  不然冲走你的眼镜
Tell me, or the glasses get a swirly!
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about!
我也看不清你在做什么
And I can't see what you're doing!
我正准备把你的眼镜扔进马桶呢
I'm holding your glasses over the toilet!
露易丝  对不起  乔迪
Louise! Sorry, Jodi.
我帮你把眼镜拿回来
Let me get your glasses back for you.
等等  你在做什么呢
Wait, now what are you doing?
就是我常做的  哈气在镜片上
Just that thing where I breathe on the lenses
然后用衬衫擦干净
and wipe them off with my shirt.
我差一点就审问出来了
I was just about to break her!
你惹出太多麻烦了
You're causing too much trouble!
至少我还在做事啊
At least I'm doing something.
你就知道编带子  鬼知道是啥玩意
While you're making lanyards, whatever those are,
这些卑鄙勾当都是我在做
I'm the one doing the dirty work.
卑鄙勾当到此为止了  露易丝
No more dirty work, Louise. I think...
你还是离队吧
I think you should leave the troop.
可  可内奸监察队怎么办
Wha... What about mole patrol?!
我喊停了
I'm shutting it down.
这是警笛消失的声音
That was the sound of the siren shutting down.
好吧  行  我走就是了
Okay, fine, I will leave.
真是个好主意
That's a great idea!
-是吗  -是
- Oh, it is? - Oh, yeah!
-不心痛吗  -不会
- So no hard feelings? - Nope!
好了  各位
All right, everyone,
我们来做牛奶纸盒喂鸟器
let's make milk carton bird feeders.
最后做个牛奶纸盒喂鸟器再上路如何
One last milk carton bird feeder for the road?
再见
Good-bye!
拜  回家见
Bye. See you at home.
你们哪个幸运儿
Which one of you lucky mamajammas
穿得下14号靴子
wears a size 14 boot and isn't all hung up
而且不介意两只鞋不一样的
about having one for each foot?
吉恩  你穿的什么玩意
Gene, what are you wearing?
垃圾时尚  简称垃时
Trash fashion. I call it trashion.
是不是该带你去打个破伤风
We should probably get you a tetanus shot.
贝尔彻家
Belcher residence.
蒂娜  你能告诉爸妈
Tina, can you tell Mom and Dad
我晚饭迟点回去吗
I'll be late for dinner?
我的会议延时了
My meeting's running long.
但愿老妈不会太难过
I hope Mom doesn't get too upset.
好的  等等  什么会议
Oh, okay. Wait, what meeting?
就是个团会而已
Oh, just a troop meeting.
你懂的
You know how it goes.
了解  好的好的
Got it. Oh, yeah, yeah.
什么团
What troop?
257团  蒂娜
Troop 257, Tina.
你加入257团了吗
You joined Troop 257?
不  露易丝  你不能那样
No, Louise, you can't do that.
他们是敌团
They're the enemy troop.
太迟了  挂了  拜拜
Too late. Got to go. Bye-bye!
喂  露易丝
Hello? Louise?
大家来认识下新成员
Let's get to know our newest member.
2-5-7团
Troop 2-5-7!
你们比其它的雷娘团有趣多了  对吧
You guys are the fun-dergirls over here, am I right?
头开得不错  不错
Good start, good start.
新来的
New girl,
你叫什么
I didn't catch your name.
-艾拉妮丝  -你刚才说你从哪转来的
- Alanis. - Where'd you say you moved from again?
纽约  纽约
New York, New York.
-我表姐也...  -不是那个纽约
- Oh, my cousin... - Not the one in New York.
是密歇根的"纽约纽约"
New York, New York, Michigan.
我们接下来做什么  串手链吗
Hey, so what are we doing, making bracelets?
手链
Bracelets?
姑娘们  今天做木雕如何
Girls, why don't you do some wood carving today?
行啊  刻什么呢
Okay! What are we whittling?
可以刻个熊  或者刻个心
Well, you could whittle a bear or a heart...
我们要刻小刀
We're whittling knives!
姑娘们刻你们的小刀吧
You girls and your knives!
伙计们  抱歉  我放学晚了
Hey, guys, sorry... I had to stay late at school.
上了节欺凌课  我给人上的
We had a bullying lesson. From me.
2-5-7
2-5-7!
-那是什么玩意儿  -我们的握手方式
- What the hell was that? - Our handshake.
入乡随俗吧  小妞
Love it or lick it, snurb.
我已经爱上它了呢  小妞
Hey, I love it already, snurb.
不  是这样
No, it's like this.
2-5-7
2-5-7!
棒极了  再做一遍
That's awesome! Do it again!
行啊  一起来
All right. Rock and roll.
姑娘们
Oh, girls.
2-5-7
2-5-7!
进展如何
How's it going?
-有头绪吗  -我找到了几个
- Any leads yet? - I did some research
很棒的休息去处
on good places to go on our retreat.
我觉得我们可以呆在一起
I thought we could all spend some time together,
聊聊天  营造一个让人放松的氛围
talk, create a safe environment.
我们没时间去营造什么放松的氛围
We don't have time to create a safe environment!
吉妮  我怎么
Ginny, I couldn't help
老闻到一股发霉的味道
but notice it smells kind of moldy in here.
于是我列了几个可能散发霉味的人
And so I have a couple names of really good mold people...
现在没空  乔迪
Not now, Jodi!
我  我把名单放这儿了
I'll just... I'll leave the list over here.
我让你回来是调查内奸的
I brought you back in here to do a job.
我的胶带钱包黏头发上了
My duct tape wallet got stuck in my hair.
-那就把头发剪了  丽娜  -好吧
- Well, then cut your hair, Rena! - Okay.
下周就是饼干销售的截止日了
The cookie deadline is next week.
如果在那之前我们没能抓出内鬼
If we don't catch the mole before then,
我们团就完了
this troop is done!
我该怎么办  我该怎么办
What do I do, what do I do?
对不起  雷娘军  我让你们失望了
I'm sorry, Thundergirls, I've let you down.
也许露易丝是对的
Maybe Louise was right...
我的确没那能耐
I don't have what it takes.
我是个失败的雷娘老太婆
I'm just a washed-up old Thunderhag!
混蛋
Son of a bitch.
*啦啦啦金发美女*
*La, la, la-la, la, la blonde *
*La-la, la, la, la, blonde... *
-琳  这张单你搞错了  -我吗
- Lin, you've messed up this order. - Blonde?
这是你今天第三次下错单了
That's the third time today you've got an order wrong,
-我们今天一共就三个客人  -我吗
- and we've only had three customers. - Blonde?
我还在收银机里
Yeah, and I found a bunch of cheese slices
发现一堆芝士片
in the cash register.
是不是金发会让人变蠢啊
I think being blonde is making me dumb.
不  是你染了金发以后
No, it's that you haven't paid attention
做什么事都变得心不在焉
to anything else but your hair since you dyed it.
不  真的  我觉得我变蠢了
No, really, I feel kind of dumb.
-你本来就有点蠢  -鲍勃
- Well, you are kind of dumb. - Bob!
我开玩笑的啦  我开玩笑的
I'm kidding. I am kidding.
-你老聪明了  -看吧
- You're very smart. - Oh, see?
我连玩笑话都听不懂了
I don't get kidding anymore.
琳达
Linda?
来看看这位
Who's that brown-haired beauty
走进你们餐厅的棕发美女
spinning around in your restaurant?
她是谁啊  是我...
Who's that girl? It's m...
我好晕
I really am dizzy,
真的  天哪  帮我一把  天哪
I really... Oh, boy. Help me up, please. Oh, my God.
格雷琴  你又染成棕色了吗
Gretchen, you're a brunette now?
我现在成理发店的蒂娜・菲了
I'm like the Tina Fey of my salon now.
美国女演员  棕发
大家都觉得我既聪明又有趣
Everyone thinks I'm so smart and funny.
是么  -对  你怎么样
Really? - Yeah. So, how's it going,
詹姆斯・金发[谐音]
James Blonde?
我开玩笑呢
That's one of my jokes.
你可能听不懂  因为你是金发
You might not get it 'cause you're blonde.
我听得懂  格雷琴  应该懂了
I do get it, Gretchen. I think.
我要去图书馆勾搭学霸咯
Well, I'm off to the library to pick up smart guys.
回见  格雷琴
Good-bye, Gretchen.
问个问题  鲍勃  你觉得这头发如何
Real quick, Bob, what do you think of the hair?
我换颜色了
I changed it.
-我知道  嗯  -回见  格雷琴
- I know. Yep. - Good-bye, Gretchen!
人人都爱棕发女郎
You know what they say...
你知道的  拜拜
Once you go brown. Bye!
露易丝
Louise.
-蒂娜  -绶带不错
- Tina. - Nice sash...
只是号码不对
Except for the numbers on it.
侦探工作干得不错
Nice detective work...
只是也没抓出内鬼
Except for not catching the mole.
顺便告诉你  我要去开会了
By the way, I'm heading to a meeting right now.
刚得到一条重磅饼干情报
A huge cookie lead just came in.
看来得我一个人搞定了
So I guess I got to go solve this thing all by myself.
替我问候257团
Well, say hi to 257 for me.
还是别了  我讨厌她们
But don't, because I hate them.
说"讨厌"也许有点过了  不过
I mean, "Hate" Is a strong word, but...
好了  你慢慢纠结吧
Okay, while you're finishing that thought,
我去捉内鬼了
I'm gonna go catch the mole.
-雷娘军万岁  -雷娘军万岁
- Thundergirls forever! - Thundergirls forever.
我们是2-5-7
We're 2-5-7!
告诉他们
Tell 'em!
我们的饼干要怎样
What do we do with cookies?
卖光光
Sell 'em!
我们的安全带该怎么样
And what do we do with seat belts?
-闭嘴  -好吧  我开慢点
- Shut up! - Okay, I'll-I'll just drive slow.
伸手指
Fingers in!
2-5-7
2-5-7!
我们是怎么得到饼干销售情报的
How'd we find out about this cookie lead?
我挺好奇
I'm just curious.
你们的情报好像源源不断啊
I mean, you guys seem to have a lot of leads.
我们到咯
We're here!
不是吧
Oh, no.
你知道这地方么
You know this place?
这地儿嘛  额
This place? Blech!
我有次在这食物中毒了
Yeah, I got food poisoning here.
恶心死了  你知道吗  我都不想进去
Gross! You know what? I can't even go in.
我会  吐的
I'm gonna, like, throw up.
你说啥呢  艾拉妮丝
What are you talking about, Alanis?
你得来帮忙搬饼干啊
You've got to help carry cookies.
好吧  马上来
Fine. Be right there.
得调整下我的绶带
Just got to adjust my sash.
有人被绶带勒死的吗
It's... does anybody's sash just choke you?
没有
No.
嘿  雷娘军
Hi, Thundergirls.
是你们要买饼干吗
Are you the cookie buyer?
不是啊  是的  不是  什么呀
No... yeah... no. What?
是你们要买五百盒饼干吗
You wanted to buy 500 boxes of cookies?
我们不需要
No, we didn't.
-我要了  -吉恩  不行
- I'll take 'em. - Gene, no.
-70块  -不  不要70
- Fine, 70. - No, not 70.
-在这儿签字  -450
- Sign here. - 450?
-别签  -签这儿  -露易丝
- Don't sign that. - Just sign it. - Louise?
你怎么穿着雷娘军制服
Why are you dressed like a Thundermummy?
露易丝
Louise?
你肯定是认错人了
you must have me confused with someone else.
我叫艾拉妮丝
I'm Alanis.
-啥  -露易丝  怎么回事
- What? - Louise, what's going on?
他们为什么会以为我们要买饼干
Why do they think we want cookies?
他俩为啥要叫你露易丝
Why do these people keep calling you Louise?
因为我俩刚好是她的父母
These people happen to be her parents.
等等  蒂娜去哪儿了  这是什么团
Wait. Where's Tina? What troop is this?
2-5-7!
你俩是我父母
These people are her parents?
他们说啥呢
What are they saying?!
拜
Well, bye!
看看谁来了
Hey, look who it is.
我完全不认识
People that I just don't even know,
因为我没加入过她们
because I'm not in that troop.
露易丝  蒂娜发短信让我们赶紧过来
Louise! Tina sent us a 911 text to meet her here.
发生什么事了
What's going on?
我们也想知道  艾拉妮丝
That's what we'd like to know, Alanis.
你们来这儿做什么  257团
What are you guys doing here, 257?
-这是我们的地盘  -要吵架吗
- This is our turf. - Are we rumbling, or what?
-天呐  -等等  拉蕊莎
- Oh, my God! - Hold on, Larissa.
让艾拉妮丝告诉我们这是怎么回事
Alanis is gonna tell us what's going on.
我可以解释这一切
There's a good explanation for everything
但得等我出去想好了再说
that I'm gonna tell you when I think of it outside.
-我去  -我可以解释
- Oh! Geez! - I can explain what's going on.
我知道谁是内鬼了
I know who the mole is.
你们现在都用夏威夷果
You guys are making banana nut fudge cookies
做香蕉饼干了吗
with macadamias now?!
蒂娜  怎么回事
Tina, what is going on?
我干嘛要去染金发
Why did I dye my hair blonde?
我现在啥都听不懂了
I don't understand anything anymore!
我说  我知道内鬼是谁了
I said, I know who the mole is.
请允许我解释
Allow me to explain.
在初版的《雷娘军指南》里有这么一句话
In the original edition of the Thundergirls handbook,
"要想逮兔子
It says "If you want to trap a rabbit,
设一个陷阱可不够  得设五个"
you don't set one trap, you set five."
我给所有人都泄露了一条假的饼干情报
I gave all of you a fake cookie lead,
都是海洋大道的不同位置
each one at a different location on Ocean Avenue.
然后我开始监视海洋大道
Then I staked out Ocean Avenue,
我知道257一定会在收到假情报后出现
knowing that 257 would show up to one of the fake leads.
我带了够用几天的食物  日常用品和厕纸
I brought enough food, supplies and toilet paper for days.
还好  我还没用完第一卷她们就出现了
Luckily, they showed up before I finished my first roll.
落网
Gotcha.
于是我就发短信给所有人让你们来这儿
That's when I texted everyone to come meet me here.
很厉害嘛
That's impressive.
好吧  我还是没听懂
Okay, I am still lost.
所以内鬼是谁
So, who was it?
我只能说  她的名字和"蒂娜"押韵
Let's just say it rhymes with "Tina."
-是你吗  -不  是丽娜
- It's you?! - No, it's Rena.
丽娜
Rena!
这是真的吗
Is that true?
我才不是内鬼呢
I'm not a mole!
蒂娜  万一是你让257团来这儿的呢
Tina, how do we know you didn't tell Troop 257 to come here?
这不是你家的餐厅吗
This is your family's restaurant.
是啊  有道理
yeah, good point.
-对啊  -等等
- Yeah! - Hold on a sec.
我在丽娜的垃圾里发现了这个
I found these in Rena's trash!
那又怎样  不就是我的旧足球鞋吗
So? Those are my old soccer cleats.
我穿刚好合适
Well, they fit me perfectly,
我要感谢你
and I'm grateful to you!
这根本是无稽之谈
This is ridiculous.
蒂娜显然是想诬陷我
Tina's obviously trying to frame me.
-蒂娜  -不不  我没有
- Tina?! - No! No, I'm not.
我没诬陷她
I'm not framing her.
等等  丽娜
Wait, Rena.
2-5-7!
丽娜真的是内鬼
Rena is the mole!
我猜对了  我就知道  我就知道是你
I was right! I knew it! I knew it was you!
可来的路上你不还说是我吗
But you just accused me on the ride over here.
对  你还说是我呢
Yeah, you accused me, too.
总之我知道是某人
I knew it was someone!
我唯一搞不懂的是你为什么要这样
The only thing I couldn't figure out was why...
为什么  丽娜
why'd you do it, Rena?
我成为雷娘军的头几年是在257度过的
My first year as a Thundergirl was in Troop 257...
那是我人生中最好的时光
best year of my life.
我们当时正为卖饼干的事和119团互掐
We were in a vicious cookie turf battle with Troop 119.
我们不得不采取极端措施
Drastic measures had to be taken.
我被选中参加一项特殊任务
I was selected for a very special assignment...
我要离开我深爱的团
to leave the troop I love
假装爱上了我痛恨的团
and pretend to love the troop I hate.
我们一直把你当朋友
We thought you were our friend!
我们一起编的那些友谊手链都一文不值吗
All these friendship bracelets, did they mean nothing?
你是说缠手上的这玩意儿
You mean this arm garbage?
拉蕊莎
Larissa.
天  我还以为蒂娜太把雷娘军当回事了
Geez. I thought Tina took this Thundergirl stuff seriously.
-你们比她还要夸张  -没错
- You guys are intense. - Yeah.
你们简直就像是
You're like Linda Hamilton
生气时坐俯卧撑的琳达・汉密尔顿
when she does all those angry pull-ups.
美国女演员  曾出演《终结者》系列电影
为蒂娜欢呼
Let's cheer for Tina!
得了吧
Come on.
我们走
Let's get out of here.
等等  我们还想买你们的饼干呢
Oh, wait! We want to buy your cookies!
-不  -好吧  不买了
- No! - Oh, right, right. No.
有了这幅眼镜  我的垃圾套装就齐了
With these glasses, my garbage ensemble is complete.
不错
It's good.
真不敢相信  我觉得还蛮好看的
I can't believe I'm gonna say this,  but I love it.
别人的废物  吉恩的衣服
One man's trash is Gene's next outfit.
下次你去挑的时候给我也选几件
Pick me out something next time you go.
你想要什么味儿的
What do you like to smell like?
给我点惊喜吧
Surprise me.
又刚开完一次雷娘军会议
Well, another great Thundergirls meeting.
看  我得到了一枚"聪明猫头鹰"勋章
Look... I got a "Wise owl" Patch
因为我展现出了年长的雷娘军才有的智慧
for demonstrating the wisdom of an older Thundergirl.
祝贺你  小蒂
Got to hand it to you, T.
这是你应得的
You earned that patch...
你找出了内鬼  拯救了你的团
you caught the mole and saved the troop.
我知道  我刚已经说过了
I-I know... I just said that.
这么说你又回雷娘军了哦
So you're sticking with the Thundergirls, huh?
我还指望你已经
I kind of hoped you were done
和你人生的这一段漫长篇章告别了呢
with that extremely long chapter of your life.
内鬼检查队成员会怀念那段时光的
The mole patrol's gonna miss hanging out with each other.
才不会  好吧  也许吧
No. I mean, maybe.
你有点吃雷娘军的醋
You were a little jealous of the Thundergirls.
因为她们抢走了你的姐姐
Taking your big sister away...
真有眼力  琳达
that's very insightful, Linda.
我又回来啦
I'm back!
我感觉我现在都能读书了
I feel like I could read a book!
露易丝  随时欢迎你回到119团
Louise, you could always come back to Troop 119.
算了  雷娘军是你的
Thundergirls is your bag,
真要加入  我估计也是去257
and if I had to, I would probably join Troop 257.
但要是发生谋杀或涉毒案  记得叫我
But if there's a murder or a drug sting, call me.
我给你编了一条友谊手链
Well, I made this friendship bracelet for you.
你知道的  我不太爱戴首饰
Eh, you know, I'm not really a jewelry person.
那就别戴了
You don't have to wear it.
不  我要戴  永远戴着
No, I'm gonna wear it forever.
走开点
Back off.
2-5-7!